

CONTACT ME AT

- alrobwilloliver@gmail.com
- www.alanoliver.dev
 www.github.com/alrobwilloliver
- www.linkedin.com/in/alanoliver-3a28aa118/

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Full Stack Development
- Node JS
- Go
- Git
- TypeScript
- Agile Development
- MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB
- Heroku
- Test Driven Development
- Linux

AWARDS RECEIVED

- Outstanding Student Awards British Council Mandarin
 Scholarship Spring and
 Summer Semesters (2018)
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award (2016)
- Year Group Best English Student (2016)

ALAN OLIVER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software engineer with 2 years experience, now working for a Blockchain company in Node JS and Go building gRPC APIs with a REST Gateway on the backend. I am passionate about creating products that solve customer problems, enthusiastic to share knowledge and ideas, like to learn quickly and adapt when facing new challenges and I am proactive about looking for ways to improve processes or code.

I am also passionate about Test Driven Development, maintaining and updating our testing suite for our SQL queries in Docker and our API endpoints in my most recent role.

One recent achievement in my role was fully testing and fixing bugs in our billing system in native Go tests and updating database values from float64 to a more precise decimal library completely independently.

In my spare time I enjoy learning about monetary policy, speaking Mandarin Chinese and travelling.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer

Cudo Ventures | March 2021 - present

- Develop new features on and maintain existing RESTful and gRPC API.
- Contribute to backend microservice infrastructure in Golang and Node.js.
- Implement, update and maintain tests for software to ensure reliability.
- Implement front end features in TypeScript VueJS

Junior Developer

New Verve Consulting | August 2020 - March 2021

- Develop user focused frontend features for an Atlassian Marketplace app in React JS.
- Implement tests for software to ensure reliability.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Online Courses

March 2021 - June 2022

- Test With Go Jon Calhoun
- gRPC [Golang] Master Class: Build Modern API & Microservices - Stephane Marek

LeWagon FullStack Coding Bootcamp

Chengdu, China | June 2019 - September 2019

- HTML, JavaScript, CSS
- Git, Heroku, APIs, command line
- MySQL, MVC architecture, Ruby on Rails